<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Owasp Project on Open Security Summit 2018</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/topics/owasp-project/</link><description>Recent content in Owasp Project on Open Security Summit 2018</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://2018.open-security-summit.org/topics/owasp-project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Application Security Verification Standard</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/owasp-projects/working-sessions/application-security-verification-standard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/owasp-projects/working-sessions/application-security-verification-standard/</guid><description>The OWASP Application Security Verification Standard (ASVS) Project provides a basis for testing web application technical security controls and a list of requirements for secure development for developers.
Why The Application Security Verification Standard is a list of application security requirements or tests that can be used by architects, developers, testers, security professionals, and even consumers to define what a secure application is.
ASVS has two main goals:
to help organizations develop and maintain secure applications to allow security service, security tools vendors, and consumers to align their requirements and offerings What Risk analysis is always subjective and this is why we expect that there will most likely never be a 100% agreement on this standard.</description></item><item><title>Creation of Security Buttons</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/owasp-projects/working-sessions/security-buttons/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/owasp-projects/working-sessions/security-buttons/</guid><description>Why Oftentimes motivating security champions is a challenge. Most of the time, they&amp;rsquo;re not willing to dedicate the time and effort to the invisible part of security. The product owners themselves focus on pushing the developement of features therefore the nessecity of security is often neglected or almost completely overlooked.
That is why there is a need to visualize the investment in security, made by a champion or an entire team.</description></item><item><title>Owasp Cloud Security Workshop (BETA)</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/owasp-cloud-security-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/owasp-cloud-security-workshop/</guid><description>The OWASP Cloud Security project aims to help people secure their products and services running in the cloud by providing a set of easy to use threat and control BDD stories that pool together the expertise and experience of the development, operations, and security communities.
This working session is a beta of the project workshop that introduces the following topics:
Behaviour Driven Development (BDD) Threat modeling Using BDD for cloud security WHY We believe that cyber security has a fundamental role to play in protecting the digital future.</description></item><item><title>OWASP Collective Defence Cluster (CDC) - One year on</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/ciso/working-sessions/owasp-collective-defence-agreement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/ciso/working-sessions/owasp-collective-defence-agreement/</guid><description>This Working Session aims to continue the work done at the last Summit on this CDC model.
Why In the same way that countries use NATO Collective defence - Article 5 to:
create a unique and enduring principle that binds its members together, committing them to protect each other and setting a spirit of solidarity within the Alliance (http://www.nato.int/cps/cn/natohq/topics_110496.htm)
companies should share information, knowledge, and resources so that malicious activities are easily detected and mitigated.</description></item><item><title>OWASP Defect Dojo</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/owasp-defect-dojo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/owasp-defect-dojo/</guid><description>An open source vulnerability management tool that streamlines the testing process by offering templating, report generation, metrics, and baseline self-service tools.
DefectDojo is a tracking tool written in Python / Django. DefectDojo was created in 2013 and open-sourced on March 13th, 2015. The project was started to make optimizing vulnerability tracking less painful. The top goal of DefectDojo is to reduce the amount of time security professionals spend logging vulnerabilities. DefectDojo accomplishes this by offering a templating system for vulnerabilities, imports for common vulnerability scanners, report generation, and metrics.</description></item><item><title>OWASP DevSecOps Studio</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/owasp-devsecops-studio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/owasp-devsecops-studio/</guid><description>DevSecOps Studio is one of its kind, self contained DevSecOps environment/distribution to help individuals in learning DevSecOps concepts. It takes lots of efforts to setup the environment for training/demos and more often, its error prone when done manually. DevSecOps Studio is easy to get started, mostly automatic and battle tested during our Free Practical DevSecOps Course at https://www.teachera.io/devsecops-course/
Why and What DevSecOps Studio project aims to reduce the time to bootstrap the environment and help you in concentrating on learning/teaching DevSecOps practices with the following features.</description></item><item><title>Owasp Testing Guide v5</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/owasp-projects/working-sessions/owasp-testing-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/owasp-projects/working-sessions/owasp-testing-guide/</guid><description>OWASP Testing Guide provides a “low level” Penetration Testing guide describing tools &amp;amp; techniques used for testing the most common application security vulnerabilities. The Guide has become a de facto standard to perform Web Application Penetration Testing.
When Starting the new OWASP Testing Guide Thu, Jun 7, 2018 2:00 PM - 3:00 PM London Time
Please join the meeting from your computer, tablet or smartphone. https://global.gotomeeting.com/join/898796925 First GoToMeeting? Let&amp;rsquo;s do a quick system check: https://link.</description></item><item><title>Owasp Top 5 Machine Learning risks</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/owasp-projects/working-sessions/owasp-top-5-machine-learning-risks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/owasp-projects/working-sessions/owasp-top-5-machine-learning-risks/</guid><description>Why Deep Learning and Machine Learning become vital part of critical systems like self-driving cars, advanced authentication and automated detection of lesions/tumors. However, research shows that such technologies have inherent risks originated from the process of how the models are being learnt or used. In this session we will learn about OWASP project (Top 5 Machine Learning Risks) which tries to identify and document these risks in general, and then we will discuss one case study about specific risk and how to address it.</description></item><item><title>Reboot Owasp Books Project</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/owasp-projects/working-sessions/reboot-owasp-books-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/owasp-projects/working-sessions/reboot-owasp-books-project/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Zap - How to use it</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/owasp-projects/user-sessions/zap-how-to-use-it/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/owasp-projects/user-sessions/zap-how-to-use-it/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>