<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mobile Security on Open Security Summit 2018</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/topics/mobile-security/</link><description>Recent content in Mobile Security on Open Security Summit 2018</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://2018.open-security-summit.org/topics/mobile-security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automation of MASVS with BDD</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/owasp-projects/working-sessions/automating-masvs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/owasp-projects/working-sessions/automating-masvs/</guid><description>The version 1.0 fixed hyphen release of the Mobile Application Security Verification Standard (MASVS) was published earlier this year. The project is getting positive feedback from all over the world and is becoming an accepted industry best practice for mobile apps. The MASVS establishes baseline security requirements for mobile apps that are useful in many scenarios, including:
In the SDLC - to establish security requirements to be followed by solution architects and developers; In mobile app penetration tests - to ensure completeness and consistency in mobile app penetration tests; In procurement - as a measuring stick for mobile app security, e.</description></item><item><title>Testing iOS Apps without Jailbreak</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/owasp-projects/working-sessions/ios-testing-without-jailbreak/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/owasp-projects/working-sessions/ios-testing-without-jailbreak/</guid><description>This user session is based on the chapter &amp;ldquo;Dynamic analysis on non-jailbroken devices&amp;rdquo; from the MSTG, see also https://github.com/OWASP/owasp-mstg/blob/5add048ae91813151c09b6ad18a5f7e63e5290d6/Document/0x06b-Basic-Security-Testing.md#dynamic-analysis-on-non-jailbroken-devices
Please install the pre-requisites: https://github.com/sensepost/objection/wiki/Patching-iOS-Applications
A MacBook with Xcode is needed!
Outcomes Every participant should have a working setup to test iOS apps without jailbreak.
Who The target audience for this Working Session is:
iOS Developers Penetration Testers Everyone else who is interested in mobile security and some technical know-how :-)</description></item><item><title>Update MSTG with changes in Android 8 (Oreo)</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/owasp-projects/working-sessions/mstg-update-android/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/owasp-projects/working-sessions/mstg-update-android/</guid><description>The Mobile Security Testing Guide (MSTG) is a comprehensive manual for mobile app security testing and reverse engineering. It describes technical processes for verifying the controls listed in the OWASP Mobile Application Verification Standard (MASVS).
Why With every (major) release of Android security controls are added/changed or may become obsolete. This session is to identify these changes in Android 8 and to update the MSTG along the way.
Outcomes An updated Android chapter in the MSTG that covers the latest changes of security controls in Android 8.</description></item><item><title>Update MSTG with changes in iOS 11</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/owasp-projects/working-sessions/mstg-update-ios/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/owasp-projects/working-sessions/mstg-update-ios/</guid><description>The Mobile Security Testing Guide (MSTG) is a comprehensive manual for mobile app security testing and reverse engineering. It describes technical processes for verifying the controls listed in the OWASP Mobile Application Verification Standard (MASVS).
Why With every (major) release of iOS security controls are added/changed or may become obsolete. This session is to identify these changes in iOS 11 and to update the MSTG along the way.
Outcomes An updated iOS chapter in the MSTG that covers the latest changes of security controls in iOS 11.</description></item></channel></rss>