<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>FAQs and Logistics on Open Security Summit 2018</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/</link><description>Recent content in FAQs and Logistics on Open Security Summit 2018</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 17:22:38 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Attendee Information</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/attendee-information/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 17:22:38 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/attendee-information/</guid><description>Welcome to Open Security Summit 2018 Thank you for your interest in Open Security Summit 2018 (OSS 2018).
The attendee general flow (attendee journey) is as follows;
Please buy a ticket (note: remote participants do not need to register to Eventbrite) Create personal page as participant to the summit Find sessions that you are interested in by viewing the topic index, tracks view or just simply list working, user or product sessions.</description></item><item><title>Accommodation</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/accommodation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/accommodation/</guid><description>Accommodation 1. When can I check in to my room? Keys will be available from 4.30pm-8.00pm on Monday 4 June at The Venue. After that, keys will be available from 8.30am to 8.00pm. Anyone arriving after 8.00pm will need to pick their keys up at the security gate.
When you leave, please return your keys to the registration desk, NOT the venue&amp;rsquo;s bins.
2. Is there somewhere I can leave my luggaage on Monday before my villa becomes available?</description></item><item><title>Content support</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/content-support/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/content-support/</guid><description>How do I get my schedule fixed or my profile page updated? Create a Pull Request or email info@opensecsummit.org with the details.</description></item><item><title>Different session types (keynote, working, user, product)</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/session-types/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/session-types/</guid><description>Working Sessions Working Sessions focus on creating and evolving ideas, in order to create outcomes that will have an impact in the real world. They are a great way to join a group of practitioners to share expertise and knowledge on a particular subject.
Find more details on the current Working Sessions
User Sessions User Sessions are much more practical sessions, which will enable you to learn new skills or develop existing ones.</description></item><item><title>I need help</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/i-need-help/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/i-need-help/</guid><description>Summit Slack channel invite link hereThe Summit team is here to help you both before and during the Summit.
Please find below some frequently asked questions on how and where you can find help during and before the Summit starts.
How to find help? Join us on Slack Get in touch via Slack on os-summit.slack.com workspace.
We have various channels to support the topics that interest you.
#oss-general</description></item><item><title>I'd like to join the Summit</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/id-like-to-join-the-summit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/id-like-to-join-the-summit/</guid><description>Summit Slack channel invite link hereHow do I buy a ticket? You will find information on buying tickets here
Where can I stay? As of Saturday 2 June, on-site accomodation is booked out. You can look for accomodation here
The Summit team cannot help you find off-site accomodation.
How can I register as a participant? TThe attendee general flow (attendee journey) is as follows;
Please buy a ticket (note: remote participants do not need to register to Eventbrite) Create personal page as participant to the summit Find sessions that you are interested in by viewing the topic index, tracks view or just simply list working, user or product sessions.</description></item><item><title>I'm a remote participant</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/im-a-remote-participant-faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/im-a-remote-participant-faq/</guid><description>Summit Slack channel invite link hereHow do I find the daily schedule for remote participants? The latest version of the schedule is online at https://open-security-summit.org/schedule/all/ Daily schedule: 8:30 – 9:20 Breakfast and Registration 9:20 - 10:30 Keynotes 10:30 - 12:30 Sessions 12:30 - 13:30 Lunch 13:30 – 15:00 Sessions 14:30 - 15:00 Sessions 15:00 - 15:30 Break 15:30 - 16:30 Sessions 16:30 – 17:30 Sessions 18:00 - 19:00 Dinner 19:30 – 21:00 Sessions 21:00 - 23:00 Sessions</description></item><item><title>I'm an on-site participant</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/im-an-on-site-participant/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/im-an-on-site-participant/</guid><description>Summit Slack channel invite link hereThe Summit team is here to help you both before and during the Summit.
Please find below some information for on-site aprticipants.
How do I get to the venue? You can travel to the Summit by rail or by car. Thameslink offers a service from London St Pancras International to Flitwick Train Station, which takes approximately 50 minutes. Flitwick station is approximately 3 miles, or a 10-minute transfer away; taxis are available at the station.</description></item><item><title>I'm an organiser</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/im-an-organiser/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/im-an-organiser/</guid><description>Summit Slack channel invite link hereWhat are my responsibilities? The organiser&amp;rsquo;s main responsibility is to create the most effective and productive working session environment for the participants.
The organiser&amp;rsquo;s main duties cover Working Session content &amp;amp; outcomes. The energy you bring to your working session will greatly impact its success.
How should I prepare for the session I&amp;rsquo;m organising? As the organiser, you should have a clear idea of what will happen during the Working Session, as this will allow each session to create something tangible and actionable.</description></item><item><title>Infrastructure needs</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/infrastructure-needs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/infrastructure-needs/</guid><description>1. What infrastructure will be available at the Venue? We will try to setup some Docker servers and maybe even a Kubernetes or Open Stack set-up, depending on needs/time.
Also we need to run a local copy of the Summit site there (together with its ELK monitoring stack).
This setup should be reachable from the Venue network, and its initial purpose will be to have the Summit site and other test sites like [JuiceShop] 2.</description></item><item><title>Organisers' Duties</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/organisers-duties/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/organisers-duties/</guid><description>1. What is the role of a working session organiser at the Open Security Summit, and what activities will I be responsible for? The Open Security Summit is a five day participant-driven event, dedicated to the collaboration of Development and Security professionals, facilitated through numerous Working Sessions.
Each working session has an organiser, and the organiser&amp;rsquo;s main responsibility is to create the most effective and productive working environment for the participants.</description></item><item><title>Reach us in Slack</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/reach-us-in-slack/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/reach-us-in-slack/</guid><description>How to reach us in Slack? Run your internet browser and access the following link: https://os-summit.slack.com Enter your email address and password and sign in. Now you are signed in to os-summit workspace. Click on the &amp;ldquo;Channels&amp;rdquo; link located to the left side of the screen. Search for channels that you are interested in. (more details about the Slack channels for the Summit can be found here) Select the channel that you want to join and click on it.</description></item><item><title>Registering and updating information</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/registration-info/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/registration-info/</guid><description>1. How do I update my schedule and register for working sessions? In order to update your schedule, follow these steps:
Visit your profile page. For example, https://open-security-summit.org/participant/francois-raynaud/.
On the next page, add the &amp;ldquo;sessions:&amp;rdquo; that you want to attend. You can enter as many sessions as you want to attend. Each session will be added as an item in a YAML list. So just give an enter after the colon, add two spaces, and a dash &amp;lsquo;-&amp;rsquo;, another space, and the name of the title of the working session.</description></item><item><title>Remote Participant</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/remote-participants/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/remote-participants/</guid><description>How do I participate remotely? This year We created, for each room, a Google Meet link.
We do plan to provide list with links to all available rooms though which the interested remote participants can follow the sessions.
Stay tuned!</description></item><item><title>Schedule</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/schedule/</guid><description>1. The schedule looks complicated At the bottom of every workshop description use the “edit” button, to add your name to your chosen sessions. There are many workshops, to keep track of your sign-ups access your personal schedule.
2. What are dynamic sessions? Dynamic sessions take place over dinner, the topics are scheduled to particular tables. No deliverables are expected.
3. What are evening sessions? Evening sessions are self-organised, informal discussions scheduled to take place in assigned villas.</description></item><item><title>Sponsored Tickets</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/sponsored_tickets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/sponsored_tickets/</guid><description>Sources of funding There is a Community Engagement Fund that interested participants are invited to apply for.
If you are approved your ticket price drops to $1000.</description></item><item><title>Transport and Directions</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/transport-and-directions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/faq/transport-and-directions/</guid><description>Transport and Directions 1. How do I get to the Summit? You can travel to the Summit by rail or by car.
Rail
Thameslink offers a service from London St Pancras International to Flitwick Train Station, which takes approximately 50 minutes. Flitwick station is approximately 3 miles, or a 10-minute transfer away; taxis are available at the station.
For further rail information, visit National Rail.
Road
From the North using the M1</description></item></channel></rss>