<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Wardley Maps on Open Security Summit 2018</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/topics/wardley-maps/</link><description>Recent content in Wardley Maps on Open Security Summit 2018</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://2018.open-security-summit.org/topics/wardley-maps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cell based Structures for Security</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/maps-and-graphs/working-sessions/cell-based-structures-for-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/maps-and-graphs/working-sessions/cell-based-structures-for-security/</guid><description>With the widespread adoption of agile development and more organisations looking to organise themselves along the lines of the Spotify Model (Squads, Tribes, Chapters and Guides), how can security functions within those organisations take advantage of Cell Based Structures to be more responsive to the business needs, while incorporating the aptitudes and attitudes of Pioneers, Settlers and Town Planners to better meet those needs.
WHY Many of the issues that businesses suffer with, from business alignment to various forms of inertia, to one size fits all to the perils of outsourcing, are a consequence of how we organize ourselves.</description></item><item><title>Using maps to define how to capture, detect and prevent 6 real-world security incidents</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/maps-and-graphs/working-sessions/using-maps-to-define-how-to-capture-detect-and-prevent-6-real-world-security-incidents/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/maps-and-graphs/working-sessions/using-maps-to-define-how-to-capture-detect-and-prevent-6-real-world-security-incidents/</guid><description>Based on the ideas shown in the picture below</description></item><item><title>Wardley Mapping – a practical session on how to use value chain mapping</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/maps-and-graphs/user-sessions/wardley-mapping-a-practical-session-on-how-to-use-value-chain-mapping/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/maps-and-graphs/user-sessions/wardley-mapping-a-practical-session-on-how-to-use-value-chain-mapping/</guid><description>Value Chain Mapping is used for all manner of initiatives; to aid corporate strategy development, to aid organizational development, to writing Sci-Fi books, to developing huge engineering projects, or to gain situational awareness.
Why This session is for anyone that is interested in using the concepts of situational awareness to organize and run a company, department, or security function.
What: Attending this session will help you:
Understand why situational awareness matters.</description></item></channel></rss>