<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Misc on Open Security Summit 2018</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/</link><description>Recent content in Misc on Open Security Summit 2018</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ask me anything (AMA) - Meet the Experts</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/user-sessions/ama-meet-the-experts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/user-sessions/ama-meet-the-experts/</guid><description>Why &amp;lsquo;Ask Me Anything&amp;rsquo; session where tech and non-tech people can ask anything someone who is from the industry relating to his work-streams, career, issues within their companies relating to info-sec, challenges, problem-solving etc
What Ask Me Anything on work-streams career issues within their companies relating to info-sec challenges problem-solving etc Outcomes</description></item><item><title>Creating Open Source Avatao exercises</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/user-sessions/creating-open-source-avatao-exercises/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/user-sessions/creating-open-source-avatao-exercises/</guid><description>What The goal of this session is to create hands-on IT security exercises using the open-source Avatao challenge toolbox. These open-source challenges can be built and launched locally by Docker containers and optionally uploaded to the avatao online platform. The goal is to bring hands-on IT security knowledge to anyone interested in this profession. Challenge creation also helps participants to understand given vulnerabilities and security issues at a deeper level.</description></item><item><title>Diving into mobile cryptography using dynamic instrumentation with Frida</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/user-sessions/diving_into_mobile_crypto_using_dynamic_instrumentation_with_frida/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/user-sessions/diving_into_mobile_crypto_using_dynamic_instrumentation_with_frida/</guid><description>WHY This all started because Google says that the keys used for encryption in Android are protected from extraction. So we want to verify if this is really true. You can read the statement here: https://developer.android.com/training/articles/keystore/#ExtractionPrevention
What On this hands-on session we will cover the very basics of dynamic instrumentation with Frida to a more complex task consisting of the extraction of crytographic material from an app process memory. We will practice this using the OMTG-Android App from the MSTG-Hacking Playground.</description></item><item><title>Group Discussion on Learning from Digital Incidents</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/working-sessions/learning-from-digital-incidents/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/working-sessions/learning-from-digital-incidents/</guid><description>A group discussion with participants on their ideas about the state of art of the community in terms of policies and procedures for promoting learning from incidents
Why Over the last three decades fields like aviation, nuclear energy, and healthcare have put in place elaborate mechanisms to learn from serious incidents and prevent their reoccurrence. We are a small team of academics trying to understand what the state of art in the case of digital incidents is.</description></item><item><title>Hands-on JIRA Schema refactoring</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/user-sessions/hands-on-jira-schema-refactoring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/user-sessions/hands-on-jira-schema-refactoring/</guid><description>What how to use Jira customised workflows how PBX GS use Jira</description></item><item><title>Hands-on JIRA Schema refactoring (DS)</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/dynamic-sessions/hands-on-jira-schema-refactoring-ds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/dynamic-sessions/hands-on-jira-schema-refactoring-ds/</guid><description>What how to use Jira customised workflows how PBX GS use Jira</description></item><item><title>JIRA - how to use it</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/user-sessions/jira-how-to-use/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/user-sessions/jira-how-to-use/</guid><description>What how to use Jira customised workflows how PBX GS use Jira</description></item><item><title>JIRA Risk Workflow</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/user-sessions/jira-risk-workflow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/user-sessions/jira-risk-workflow/</guid><description>This JIRA Risk Workflow can be used to manage the Risk process and ensure that business owners understand the side effects of the decisions they make.
Why This workflow needs to be presented and discussed by the community.
What How does it work in practice Exporting Risk JIRA Workflow into Atlassian Marketplace Outcomes This Working Session should result in an improved JIRA Risk Workflow.
Who The target audience for this working session is:</description></item><item><title>Job Fair</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/working-sessions/job-fair/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/working-sessions/job-fair/</guid><description>Meet companies that are hiring at the Summit</description></item><item><title>Lessons learned from public bug bounties programmes</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/working-sessions/lessons-public-bug-bounties-programmes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/working-sessions/lessons-public-bug-bounties-programmes/</guid><description>A bug bounty program is a crowdsourcing initiative offering compensations for discovery and responsible disclosure of potential security vulnerabilities. Many organizations offer compenstations in terms of cash or goodies while others only offer acknolwedgements. Bug bounties are commonly seen as the most effective and inexpensive way to identify vulnerabilities in live systems and products.
Why While bug bounties are seen as a lucrative way to make quick money for researchers, it&amp;rsquo;s equally seen as an effective and inexpensive way to perform security audit for vendors/organizations.</description></item><item><title>MSc Appication Security</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/working-sessions/msc-application-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/working-sessions/msc-application-security/</guid><description>The MSc Application Security Curriculum needs more work to look at the skills and knowledge students should learnt as part of such a qualification, we had an initial attempt at gathering opinions by survey at the last summit but the majority returned surveys were “lost” before they were harvested.
We&amp;rsquo;re looking to produce a wider survey of OWASP trainers and educational supporters to canvas opinions on a wider range of generic Application Security Skills and knowledge which would be required from a MSc curriculum and determining suitable learning objectives to be able to produce an “open” curriculum for any educational institution or trainer to use.</description></item><item><title>OS Summit Website - how to use it</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/user-sessions/oss-website-how-to-use/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/user-sessions/oss-website-how-to-use/</guid><description>What How to update the Open Security website How to subscribe to sessions How to invite participants to your sessions</description></item><item><title>Security Buttons Extended</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/dynamic-sessions/security-buttons-extended/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/dynamic-sessions/security-buttons-extended/</guid><description>Why Oftentimes motivating security champions is a challenge. Most of the time, they’re not willing to dedicate the time and effort to the invisible part of security. The product owners themselves focus on pushing the developement of features therefore the nessecity of security is often neglected or almost completely overlooked.
That is why there is a need to visualize the investment in security, made by a champion or an entire team.</description></item><item><title>Security Ethics Checklist</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/working-sessions/security-ethical-checklist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/working-sessions/security-ethical-checklist/</guid><description>Security is an ethical issue. What should every single developer be asking themselves to check their code or system is safe to use before they deploy it? The aim of this session is to suggest a simple set of questions that could alert an engineer with limited security knowledge to obvious flaws in their product that could hurt unsuspecting users.
WHY Developers have to design, write, test and deploy code. They are potentially the last bastion of defence against unethical code going live but accordingly to the 2018 StackOverflow Developers Survey only 20% of us feel ultimately responsible for the behaviour of our own code.</description></item><item><title>Squad Modelling and Cross Functional Teams</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/working-sessions/squad-modelling-and-cross-functional-teams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/working-sessions/squad-modelling-and-cross-functional-teams/</guid><description>Session Structure Introduction to cross functional teams How it worked for Moonpig, The benefits that have been delivered Q&amp;amp;A WHY Six months ago Moonpig successfully rolled out cross-functional teams across their organisation, incorporating all personnel in customer-facing roles. Amanda will talk about the benefits of cross-functional teams, how Moonpig approached their restructure and the lessons they’ve learned so far.
What (&amp;hellip;)
Outcomes (&amp;hellip;)
References (&amp;hellip;)</description></item><item><title>Summit Onboarding</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/user-sessions/oss-onboarding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/user-sessions/oss-onboarding/</guid><description>Welcome participants and explain how the Summit work welcome + wifi collaborative + open source CC code of conduct schedule (fluid) type of sessions locations layout CHECK your schedule! schedule conflicts - slack https://os-summit.slack.com/messages/CAYTQHU1F website (go to the session) / subscribe to slack / #OpenSecSummit add everything to slack (photos / content &amp;hellip;) organiser responsibilities: https://open-security-summit.org/faq/organisers-duties/ participants responsibilities outcomes need to be captured need for help, like e.</description></item><item><title>Track Introductions</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/user-sessions/track-introductions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/user-sessions/track-introductions/</guid><description>Flash introductions to some of the main summit tracks</description></item><item><title>Using AI and ML for incident response</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/working-sessions/using-ai-ml-for-incident-response/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/working-sessions/using-ai-ml-for-incident-response/</guid><description>How to use AI and ML for incident response</description></item><item><title>Using Jira to handle Incident Response - simulations</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/working-sessions/using-jira-to-handle-incident-response-simulations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/working-sessions/using-jira-to-handle-incident-response-simulations/</guid><description>Incident response simulations and role play scenarios</description></item><item><title>Using press-releases as improved project's briefs</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/working-sessions/using-press-releases-as-improved-projects-briefs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/working-sessions/using-press-releases-as-improved-projects-briefs/</guid><description>Understand the press release concept for project creation and how to put it into practice</description></item><item><title>Women in Cyber-security: improving the gender balance</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/working-sessions/women-in-cyber-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/working-sessions/women-in-cyber-security/</guid><description>Why Why is there a persistent gap when it comes to gender balance in security?
Outcomes How can we as security professionals ensure there is a fair chance and representation for all?</description></item><item><title>Writing a Security Budget</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/user-sessions/writing-a-security-budget/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/user-sessions/writing-a-security-budget/</guid><description>Practical session on writing a Security Budget</description></item></channel></rss>