<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CI Pipeline on Open Security Summit 2018</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/topics/ci-pipeline/</link><description>Recent content in CI Pipeline on Open Security Summit 2018</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://2018.open-security-summit.org/topics/ci-pipeline/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Securing GitHub Integrations</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/securing-github-integrations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/securing-github-integrations/</guid><description>Why This Working Session will examine the need for secure GitHub integrations.
As more and more services are integrated with GitHub, the public and private repos of different companies are being exposed to a much wider set of attackers and threats.
Currently, the GitHub security model does not allow the granularity required to control access (for example read-access to only one repo). This means that choices tend to be limited to either:</description></item><item><title>Securing the CI Pipeline</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/securing-the-ci-pipeline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/securing-the-ci-pipeline/</guid><description>Why This Working Session will consider the securing of the CI Pipeline - A key element of DevOps.
Doing CI builds, testing, and deployments have many advantages when done correctly. Using libraries from 3rd parties in your build can be on compromised servers. Even signing your packages or artifacts automatically could result in you delivering compromised software to others.
What Identify best practice for DevOps and Developers Agree what to include in a cheat sheet for developers who use third party services Agree recommendations for 3rd party service providers (for example, provide warning messages of possible insecurities) Outcomes This Working Session will publish:</description></item><item><title>Security Crowdsourcing</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/security-crowd-sourcing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/security-crowd-sourcing/</guid><description>Security crowdsourcing is necessary - it is allowing highly talented individuals and resourceful organisations to use the power of their intelligence, skills and resources to fight cyber threats. A community can significantly have a higher efficiency level in fighting against cyber threats rather than a single body that does all by itself.
Sharing Intelligence
Effective form of crowdsourcing, governments and private companies can share their knowledge and stop or reduce potential or existing threats.</description></item></channel></rss>