<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GDPR on Open Security Summit 2018</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/</link><description>Recent content in GDPR on Open Security Summit 2018</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ask me anything (AMA) on GDPR</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/user-sessions/ask-me-anything-on-gdpr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/user-sessions/ask-me-anything-on-gdpr/</guid><description>&amp;lsquo;Ask Me Anything&amp;rsquo; session where tech and non-tech people can ask anything someone who is from the industry relating to GDPR</description></item><item><title>Creating a standard for GDPR patterns</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/working-sessions/creating-standard-for-gdpr-patterns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/working-sessions/creating-standard-for-gdpr-patterns/</guid><description>GDPR Patterns are reusable mappings of data journeys across specific threat modelling scenarios.
It aims to support the mapping of data flows and consider security and privacy requirements to meet EU GDPR regulation.
WHY Threat model diagrams are excellent sources of data mapping as they allow us to ensure a consistent model to assess threats and controls designed to mitigate those threats.
The use of GDPR Patterns permits organizations to risk assess data flows and select technical and organizational measures used to meet security and privacy requirements as set by EU GDPR</description></item><item><title>DPO how to become one</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/working-sessions/dpo-how-to-become-one/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/working-sessions/dpo-how-to-become-one/</guid><description>So You want to be a Data protection Officer?
WHY A Data Protection Officer (DPO) supervise, develops, implements and monitor a company’s Data Protection Policy and people data privacy. The DPO is responsible for the safety of personal information, minimising risk through the monitoring and development of policies. How the data is collected and updated, the security systems used, encryptions, and data sharing rules designed to keep it safe.
Under the GDPR, it is mandatory for certain controllers and processors to designate a DPO for public authorities and bodies (irrespective of what data they process).</description></item><item><title>DPO what to expect</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/working-sessions/dpo-what-to-expect/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/working-sessions/dpo-what-to-expect/</guid><description>A Data Protection Officer is acting in an independent manner.
WHY Article 38(3) establishes some basic protections to help ensure that DPOs are able to perform their tasks with a sufficient degree of autonomy within their organisation. Controllers/processors are required to ensure that the DPO &amp;ldquo;does not receive any instructions regarding the exercise of [his or her] tasks.&amp;rdquo;
What The DPO informs and advise the controller or the processor and the employees who carry out processing of their obligations under the GDPR.</description></item><item><title>European GDPR variations</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/working-sessions/european-gdpr-variations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/working-sessions/european-gdpr-variations/</guid><description>Within GRPR members there are already legal variations with national laws.
WHY Complex structural changes mean a complete overhaul to anything remotely related to data in all companies and organisations.
What Personal data All data from Austria and Switzerland should be handled according to GDPR standards. Austrian continues a national tradition of extending data protection rights to legal persons (such as corporations and nonprofit foundations) in addition to individuals. Switzerland’s data protection law currently being revised to align with the GDPR, also applies to legal as well as natural persons.</description></item><item><title>Gamification of GDPR compliance</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/working-sessions/gamification-of-gdpr-compliance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/working-sessions/gamification-of-gdpr-compliance/</guid><description>There are a lots of good things behind the GDRR
People get back the control of their personal data and it unifies the regulatory environment for international business within the EU.
WHY The old directive was dated of 1995 and most importantly it was established before the internet and the extensive use of online services. The way people and organisations create, use, share, and store information has extensively changed.
What People consent is compulsory – unless an organization gets a consent, it cannot store, use, share people personal data.</description></item><item><title>GDPR Appropriate Security Controls</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/working-sessions/gdpr-appropriate-security-controls/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/working-sessions/gdpr-appropriate-security-controls/</guid><description/></item><item><title>GDPR Compliance what does it mean?</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/working-sessions/gdpr-compliance-what-does-it-mean/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/working-sessions/gdpr-compliance-what-does-it-mean/</guid><description>GDPR Compliance what does it means for you?
On the 27th of April 2016 the European parliament and council adopted the GDPR. Enforceable from the 25th of May 2018 it replaces the 1995 Data Protection Directive.
WHY The existing directive dated of 1995 was established before the internet use, and the way people and organisations create, use, share, and store information. The GDPR is unifying the personal data privacy, protection and security.</description></item><item><title>Hands-on GDPR Patterns</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/user-sessions/hands-on-gdpr-patterns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/user-sessions/hands-on-gdpr-patterns/</guid><description>Topic Practical use of https://github.com/pbx-gs/gdpr-patterns project
What are GDPR Patterns? They are reusable mappings of data journeys across specific threat modeling scenarios.
The idea is to take the diagram below and map specific scenarios to it.
&amp;lsquo;Based on Threat Models?&amp;rsquo; Threat models diagrams are perfect sources of data mappings since they already mapped the flows of data (where it comes from and where they go to)</description></item><item><title>Meet the ICO</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/working-sessions/meet-the-ico/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/working-sessions/meet-the-ico/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Policies for the security industry</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/working-sessions/policies-for-the-security-industry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/working-sessions/policies-for-the-security-industry/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Share your security polices and release them under Creative Commons</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/working-sessions/share-your-polices-and-release-them-under-cc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/working-sessions/share-your-polices-and-release-them-under-cc/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Using graphs for GDPR mappings and visualisations</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/user-sessions/using-graphs-for-gdpr-mappings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/user-sessions/using-graphs-for-gdpr-mappings/</guid><description>Create graphs as shows in the https://github.com/pbx-gs/gdpr-patterns project</description></item><item><title>Using Threat Models for GDPR</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/user-sessions/using-threat-models-for-gdpr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/gdpr/user-sessions/using-threat-models-for-gdpr/</guid><description>Hands on user session on how to use Threat Models in GDPR mappings
This session will take place in the Photobox villa and not the SAMM villa!!!
This is villa 317</description></item></channel></rss>