<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Threat Model on Open Security Summit 2018</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/</link><description>Recent content in Threat Model on Open Security Summit 2018</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>API Threat Modeling Cheat Sheet</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-api-cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-api-cheatsheet/</guid><description>Why We all love Cheat Sheets. They are great to use when you need it but they are also great to learn because they force us to summarize the most important points.
What What are the main Threats against an API? Can we find common Threats that apply to APIs? Are there generic Threats we could check for applicability? Could we organize the Threats in Risk Patterns for APIs? Can they be summarized on a Cheat Sheet form?</description></item><item><title>Attack chains as TM technique</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-attack-chain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-attack-chain/</guid><description>WHY We need different techniques to discover threats against a system to complement the traditional ones if they do not work.
What Create attack chains as TM technique. Extedend possibly using DFD as connection maps, layered defence and attack patterns.
Outcomes An example of an attack chain.
References</description></item><item><title>Back to the future with Threat Modeling</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-back-to-the-future/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-back-to-the-future/</guid><description>Why Threat Modeling is useful to find design issues even before you&amp;rsquo;ve written a line of code, and that&amp;rsquo;s the best time to find those issues but&amp;hellip; What can we learn doing a post-mortem of a security incident?
What Many interesting questions may arise:
The vulnerabilities that were exploited during the breach were identified as a use case of any Threat? Were there some countermeasures or security requirements that didn&amp;rsquo;t worked as expected?</description></item><item><title>Create generic TM for CMS</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-creating-generic-tm-for-cms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-creating-generic-tm-for-cms/</guid><description>At the moment we still don&amp;rsquo;t have a good repository of examples of Threat Modeling diagrams.
The summit is the perfect location for all the Threat Modeling practitioners to share anonymised versions of the models they have created, so that we can consolidate them in a book.
All models will be stored in a GitHub repo and released under Creative Commons</description></item><item><title>Create generic TM for CMS</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-creating-generic-tm-for-cms2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-creating-generic-tm-for-cms2/</guid><description>At the moment we still don&amp;rsquo;t have a good repository of examples of Threat Modeling diagrams.
The summit is the perfect location for all the Threat Modeling practitioners to share anonymised versions of the models they have created, so that we can consolidate them in a book.
All models will be stored in a GitHub repo and released under Creative Commons</description></item><item><title>Creating diagrams with DOT language</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-diagrams-dot-language/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-diagrams-dot-language/</guid><description>Why One of the steps in threat modeling is diagramming your system in order to be able to communicate about it. Diagramming tools so far have been unable to store diagrams in a way that we can later make it easy for tools to read and change them. We want to show one possible way of solving this problem.
What Show a PoC of a diagramming tool using DOT langaue to save th diagram in a JSON format Discuss the possibilty of using this JSON format to also describe the rest of the threat model Come up with a unified way of storing threat models Outcomes Consensus wether this might is feasible.</description></item><item><title>Define an Open Risk Pattern format</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-risk-patterns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-risk-patterns/</guid><description>Why Threat Models can be assempled by using pre-written templates. But entire templates can be too large as a building block for a threat model. A smaller unit is called a Risk Pattern: a mini-template tied to a particular technology and/or use-case. Examples of risk patterns:
Transmitting sensitive data over untrusted networks Single factor authentication against a web app File upload to a web app OWASP would be a great repository for a shared collection of risk patterns, so the first step is to define a format for these patterns.</description></item><item><title>Describe different ways of implementing TM in agile organisations</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/implementing-tm-in-agile-organisations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/implementing-tm-in-agile-organisations/</guid><description>WHY Many organisations are struggling to fit threat modeling to their agile way of working.
What We will describe one of more ways to implement the different building blocks of threat modeling in the different actions of SCRUM and Kanban. What &amp;ldquo;deliverables&amp;rdquo; make sense in agile? For example, when during the SCRUM process would you update the model of what&amp;rsquo;s being worked on? When do you discover new threats? Who will perform what actions to get all of this done?</description></item><item><title>Docker and Kubernetes Threat Modeling Cheat Sheet</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-docker-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-docker-kubernetes/</guid><description>Why We all love Cheat Sheets. They are great to use when you need it but they are also great to learn because they force us to summarize the most important points.
What What are the main Threats against Docker and/or Kubernetes? Can we find common Threats that apply to Docker and/or Kubernetes? Are there generic Threats we could check for applicability? Could we organize the Threats in Risk Patterns for Docker and/or Kubernetes?</description></item><item><title>Federated Login with Social Platforms Threat Modeling Cheat Sheet</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-federated-login-social-platforms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-federated-login-social-platforms/</guid><description>Why We all love Cheat Sheets. They are great to use when you need it but they are also great to learn because they force us to summarize the most important points.
What What are the main Threats against a Federated Login with Social Platforms? Can we find common Threats that apply to Federated Login with Social Platforms? Are there generic Threats we could check for applicability? Could we organize the Threats in Risk Patterns for Federated Login with Social Platforms?</description></item><item><title>How do you define and measure the value of Threat Modeling?</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-value/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-value/</guid><description>Why In most organisations we need to justify the time we spend on tasks. In order to get the budget / approval to do threat modeling we should be able to show the value of threat modeling. Instead of re-iterating standard reasons we would like to define a number of things we can measure to show the value of threat modeling.
What How can we define value of threat modeling?</description></item><item><title>How to scale Threat Modeling.</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-scale-threat-modeling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-scale-threat-modeling/</guid><description>Why Manual threat modeling is typically a workshop exercise done with a whiteboard and is led by a member of the security team and some key members of the developer (and sometimes operations) team.
Organizations face three main challenges integrating Threat Modeling activities in the SDLC:
The ratio of developers to security is 100:1. Security can be a bottleneck. Continuous delivery is part of the Agile recipe. Security can be a bottleneck for each sprint.</description></item><item><title>How to Threat Model Features with Questionnaires</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-features-with-questionnaires/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-features-with-questionnaires/</guid><description>Why Threat Modeling architectural changes through STRIDE is well established. But many agile teams need to threat model code changes to an existing application, which typically does not involve large architectural changes. STRIDE can be used for this too - but if we narrow the scope to only web apps and APIs, can we find a more specific version of STRIDE that&amp;rsquo;s easier for non-experts to use?
What STRIDE is already essentially a questionnaire, e.</description></item><item><title>IoT Threat Modeling Cheat Sheet</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-iot-cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-iot-cheatsheet/</guid><description>Why We all love Cheat Sheets. They are great to use when you need it but they are also great to learn because they force us to summarize the most important points.
What What are the main Threats against an IoT device/deployment? Can we find common Threats that apply to IoT devices/deployments? Are there generic Threats we could check for applicability? Could we organize the Threats in Risk Patterns for IoT devices/deployments?</description></item><item><title>Methodology / technique showcase</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-showcases/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-showcases/</guid><description>Why We all use methodologies and techniques differently. During the showcases we will ask the participants to show any technique, methodology, process etc. where they have used / created a variation that might be of interest to the audience. This is an open floor work shop so your participation / preparation is needed!
What Showcase experiences, novell ways to use techniques, show how to implement threat modeling in specific development environments (e.</description></item><item><title>SABSA and threat modeling</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-sabsa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-sabsa/</guid><description>Why What can we learn from SABSA when it comes to securing architecture (i.e. threat modeling)
What In this session, we’re going to give security architects who are struggling to leverage the full power of SABSA in agile environments practical ways SABSA enhances and enables agile and Dev[Sec]Ops.
Specifically, we’ll cover:
• An initial summary of Agile, Agile Architecture and Dev[Sec]Ops • How SABSA makes agile faster, easier and more consistent • What foundations need to be in place to enable Agile SABSA • An iterative interpretation of the SABSA Lifecycle • A walk-through of Agile SABSA for different types of security demands</description></item><item><title>Share your Threat Models diagrams and create a Book</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-share-your-threat-models-diagrams-and-create-a-book/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-share-your-threat-models-diagrams-and-create-a-book/</guid><description>Discuss the possibility and usefulness of combining all knowledge captured on the website into a book somewhat similar to the tseting guide.</description></item><item><title>Threat model cheat sheets</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-cheatsheets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-cheatsheets/</guid><description>WHY We need to have 3 more cheat sheets for the missing TM steps.
What Create a cheat sheet of maximum 5 points, each one starting with &amp;ldquo;do&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t&amp;rdquo;
Outcomes 3 cheat sheets
References The one cheat sheet already created:
Cheat sheets: What are we building?
DO: scope to what is under your control.
DO: Understand the context your system will live in. This includes but is not limited to the environment, security controls, …</description></item><item><title>Threat model closing session</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-closing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-closing/</guid><description>WHY To list our achievements and agree on the way forward. What List our achievements for this summit Agree on the way forward Distribute tasks Outcomes List of achievements
References</description></item><item><title>Threat model guide</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-level-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-level-guide/</guid><description>WHY People are clueless on how to start with threat modeling. I propos we create a guide i the style of ASVS where we show in different levels what the steps are that can be done for threat modeling depending on the need and/or maturity of the organisation.
What A guide with some levels such as: level 0: you are not doing TM or something ad hoc level 1: you are answering some of the 4 questions but not in a structured way level 2: you do a full 4 question TM for one product level 3: you intregated the full TM in the SDLC and vary the amount/level of the TM according to the risk appetite of that application/system/product</description></item><item><title>Threat model track opening session</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-open/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-open/</guid><description>WHY Create awareness with the threat model track participants on how the summit works.Explain how the OWASP TM project works and how the community is handling things.
What Explenation of the way of working for threat modeling Introduction of the working sessions Open floor for last minute sessions Call to action Outcomes Updated agenda with working sessions and particpants
References</description></item><item><title>Threat Model training through Gamification</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-training-through-gamification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-training-through-gamification/</guid><description>Why Training is a crucial activity in AppSec. Security must abandon the silo in which it has lived the last decades to become one more indicator of the quality of a software product. And to do this we need to train people and make security something transversal. Gamification has become a very interesting alternative to train people. As children we learn by playing and we should not stop learning while we play when we become adults.</description></item><item><title>Threat Modeling Website Structure</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-website-structure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/working-sessions/tm-website-structure/</guid><description>WHY Get a concensus on the actual TM project content structure website structure.
What Explenation of the way of working for the website Review the proposed structure Start updating the website Outcomes Updated website showing at least the structure without content.</description></item><item><title>Update Treat Modeling website 1</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/user-sessions/update-the-website-update1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/user-sessions/update-the-website-update1/</guid><description>During these sessions we will update the website with the content created during the day workshops. If time permits we will also add all the content from the past summit and working sessions from the OWASP TM Slack channel.</description></item><item><title>Update Treat Modeling website 2</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/user-sessions/update-the-website-update2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/user-sessions/update-the-website-update2/</guid><description>During these sessions we will update the website with the content created during the day workshops. If time permits we will also add all the content from the past summit and working sessions from the OWASP TM Slack channel.</description></item><item><title>Update Treat Modeling website 3</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/user-sessions/update-tm-pages-on-website/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/user-sessions/update-tm-pages-on-website/</guid><description>The OWASP web site has many pages whose distinctions are hard to understand, and which carry substantial overlap and contradiction. (https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Application_Threat_Modeling, https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Threat_Risk_Modeling, https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Threat_Modeling_Cheat_Sheet, https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Category:Threat_Modeling
We need to clean them up, create a single entry point, and a comprehensible hierarchy. We need to eliminate duplication and conflict.
The goal of this session is to (1) identify what content we want (2) create it (3) remove/redirect/archive other content.
Topic (&amp;hellip;)
Target Audience (&amp;hellip;)</description></item><item><title>Update Treat Modeling website 4</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/user-sessions/update-tm-pages-on-website3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/user-sessions/update-tm-pages-on-website3/</guid><description>During these sessions we will update the website with the content created during the day workshops. If time permits we will also add all the content from the past summit and working sessions from the OWASP TM Slack channel.</description></item><item><title>Update Treat Modeling website 5</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/user-sessions/update-the-website-update4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/threat-model/user-sessions/update-the-website-update4/</guid><description>During these sessions we will update the website with the content created during the day workshops. If time permits we will also add all the content from the past summit and working sessions from the OWASP TM Slack channel.</description></item></channel></rss>