<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Visualisation on Open Security Summit 2018</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/topics/visualisation/</link><description>Recent content in Visualisation on Open Security Summit 2018</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://2018.open-security-summit.org/topics/visualisation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creating Appsec metrics and visualisation</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/user-sessions/creating-appsec-metrics-and-visualisation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/user-sessions/creating-appsec-metrics-and-visualisation/</guid><description>Why You can&amp;rsquo;t improve what you don&amp;rsquo;t measure. Its important to measure the activities as part of SDL and drive future improvements to the application security program. Metrics show business value to stakeholders and help drive further investments in the program. Metrics also help in figuring out whats working and whats not.
Metrics used should be meaningful and not there for the sake of just metrics (metric fatigue?).
What The goal of this User Session is to find ways to create meaningful metrics and dashboards for AppSec Professionals like Mean Time To Remediate, Mean Time To Find etc.</description></item><item><title>From Threat Modeling to DevSecOps metrics</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/threat-modeling-to-devsecops/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/threat-modeling-to-devsecops/</guid><description>Why What Content Outcomes Who The target audience for this Working Session is:
Developers Security professionals DevSecOps Security champions References</description></item><item><title>SOC Monitoring Visualisation</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/appsec-soc-monitoring-visualisation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/appsec-soc-monitoring-visualisation/</guid><description>Why Capturing logs and visualising them in a SOC (Security Operation Center) is a key activity in the asymmetric arms race against malicious actors and bugs.
In addition to providing high-value actionable information, a good SOC will provide a wealth of valuable metrics and visualisations for the business, from user activities and behaviour to system performance.
The Working Session will assess the role, the work, and the importance of a SOC within a business.</description></item><item><title>Using activity-oriented metrics for Security</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/activity-oriented-metrics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/activity-oriented-metrics/</guid><description>WHY Gamification of security activities is a great way to engage with teams.
Scorecard to provide better information, fun and gamification.
It uses RAG report data and provides an extra level of insights on each team. We can see the data by feature (service) team, department and for a full matrix of everything.
Every teams and services can be listed and who owns what, from the Tiering of the service to specific services (web sites, apis, databases, workers, lambdas…).</description></item></channel></rss>