<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Education on Open Security Summit 2018</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/topics/education/</link><description>Recent content in Education on Open Security Summit 2018</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://2018.open-security-summit.org/topics/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creating Open Source Avatao exercises</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/user-sessions/creating-open-source-avatao-exercises/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/user-sessions/creating-open-source-avatao-exercises/</guid><description>What The goal of this session is to create hands-on IT security exercises using the open-source Avatao challenge toolbox. These open-source challenges can be built and launched locally by Docker containers and optionally uploaded to the avatao online platform. The goal is to bring hands-on IT security knowledge to anyone interested in this profession. Challenge creation also helps participants to understand given vulnerabilities and security issues at a deeper level.</description></item><item><title>Lessons learned from public bug bounties programmes</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/working-sessions/lessons-public-bug-bounties-programmes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/working-sessions/lessons-public-bug-bounties-programmes/</guid><description>A bug bounty program is a crowdsourcing initiative offering compensations for discovery and responsible disclosure of potential security vulnerabilities. Many organizations offer compenstations in terms of cash or goodies while others only offer acknolwedgements. Bug bounties are commonly seen as the most effective and inexpensive way to identify vulnerabilities in live systems and products.
Why While bug bounties are seen as a lucrative way to make quick money for researchers, it&amp;rsquo;s equally seen as an effective and inexpensive way to perform security audit for vendors/organizations.</description></item><item><title>MSc Appication Security</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/working-sessions/msc-application-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/misc/working-sessions/msc-application-security/</guid><description>The MSc Application Security Curriculum needs more work to look at the skills and knowledge students should learnt as part of such a qualification, we had an initial attempt at gathering opinions by survey at the last summit but the majority returned surveys were “lost” before they were harvested.
We&amp;rsquo;re looking to produce a wider survey of OWASP trainers and educational supporters to canvas opinions on a wider range of generic Application Security Skills and knowledge which would be required from a MSc curriculum and determining suitable learning objectives to be able to produce an “open” curriculum for any educational institution or trainer to use.</description></item><item><title>Recruiting AppSec Talent</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/ciso/working-sessions/recruiting-appsec-talent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/ciso/working-sessions/recruiting-appsec-talent/</guid><description>AppSec and InfoSec talent are difficult to find these days, for several reasons. It is a challenge for an industry corporation to accept professionals who are unhappy with their current employment, who would like to work in a narrow fields such as security, but only have experience in other areas of IT or development. There are also many people just starting out in the industry who lack experience or certifications (usually a degree in CS) and cannot easily prove their potential to prospective employers.</description></item></channel></rss>