<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Working Sessions on Open Security Summit 2018</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/working-sessions/</link><description>Recent content in Working Sessions on Open Security Summit 2018</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://2018.open-security-summit.org/working-sessions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/working-sessions/_template/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/working-sessions/_template/</guid><description>(add intro)
WHY (&amp;hellip;)
What (&amp;hellip;)
Outcomes (&amp;hellip;)
References (&amp;hellip;)
Previous</description></item><item><title>GDPR Patterns (based on Threat Models)</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/working-sessions/pre-summit/gdpr-patterns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/working-sessions/pre-summit/gdpr-patterns/</guid><description>Next working session (17th April) You can participate online (London) or remotely. Get your ticket here
What are GDPR Patterns? They are reusable mappings of data journeys across specific threat modeling scenarios.
The idea is to take the diagram below and map specific scenarios to it.
&amp;lsquo;Based on Threat Models?&amp;rsquo; Threat models diagrams are perfect sources of data mappings since they already mapped the flows of data (where it comes from and where they go to)</description></item><item><title>Policies for the InfoSec industry</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/working-sessions/policies-for-the-infosec-industry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/working-sessions/policies-for-the-infosec-industry/</guid><description>Policies provide a clear framework for an organistion to measure how it meets its strategies and obligations, whether these be regulatory, legal, people, security etc. This session will answer key questions about the develpoment and use of policies by IT Security teams.
WHY Collaboration of ideas can make the development of policy frameworks and their use easier and more relevant to business.
What What policies should a business have and for what purpose?</description></item><item><title>Suggestions for Working Sessions</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/working-sessions/ideas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/working-sessions/ideas/</guid><description>What should we work on? The OSS philosophy is one of participant-driven focus. So it is up to you to shape your conference to target your greatest needs. There is a whole world of ideas, let&amp;rsquo;s start sharing them, prioritising them and turning them into working sessions with clear objectives.
Working Session ideas Agile AppSec Agile Practices for Security Teams Define Agile Security Practices Integrating Security into a Portfolio Kanban Integrating Security into a Sales Channel Integrating Security into an Spotify Model Security Champions Security Guild vs Security Champions Using Security Risks to Measure Agile Practices InfoSec Warranties and Guarantees Mobilising Business Lines for Security SAMM Metrics for Enterprise The future of privacy Women in Cyber CISO Application Security Guide for CISO AppSec Article 5 Collective Defence Agreement AppSec for CISOs CISO Round Table CISO Survey Cyber Insurance GDRP DPO and AppSec Growing the AppSec Industry DevSecOps AppSec SoC Monitoring Visualisation BDD for Cloud Security Docker Security ELK Security Dashboards Integrating Security Tools in SDL JIRA Risk Workflow Netflix Security Automation Node Security Round Table Real Time SAST Engine Architecture Review Docker Security Workshop Securing GitHub Integrations Securing Legacy Applications Securing the CI Pipeline Security Guidance and Feedback in IDE SRE Security Activities Threat Vulnerability Management WAF best practices Writing Security Tests Education AppSec BSc Masters Curriculum Design Creating AppSec Talent Creating AppSec Teams CTFs Cyber Security Economics Hackathon Beyond OWASP Top Ten Recruiting AppSec Talent Security Book Club Software Defined Everything (SDx) Teaching Attacker Perspective to Developers IOT GSMA IoT Security Guidelines Internet of Things Project Security Architecture Recommendations for IoT TLS for Local IoT Juice Shop Juice Shop Brainstorming Juice Shop Coding Day Juice Shop Coding Night Juice Shop Release Mobile Sec MSTG MSTG 01 MSTG 02 MSTG 03 MSTG 04 MSTG 05 Research BeyondCorp for internal Web Applications Future of .</description></item></channel></rss>