<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DevSecOps on Open Security Summit 2018</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/</link><description>Recent content in DevSecOps on Open Security Summit 2018</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/_canceled/pixi-roadmap-and-enhancement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/_canceled/pixi-roadmap-and-enhancement/</guid><description>The technical ecosystem is changing – APIs and Web Services are often underprotected.
WHY With Pixi, understand common vulnerabilities in web app and services.
The intent is to test modern web applications and API&amp;rsquo;s for security issues and how to write more secure API&amp;rsquo;s in the future.
What Pixi consists of vulnerable web services, users can exploit several of Pixi&amp;rsquo;s vulnerabilities so they can learn how to do better when they create their own web services and other types of APIs.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/_canceled/using-pixi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/_canceled/using-pixi/</guid><description>This will be a user sessions focused on using Devslop pixi, which means the MEAN Stack, API and Web Service Hacking.
Topic Modern applications often use APIs and other micro services to deliver faster and better products and services. However, there are currently few training grounds for security testing in such areas. In comes DevSlop, OWASP&amp;rsquo;s newest project, a collection of DevOps security disasters made as a vulnerable testing and proving ground for developers and security testers alike.</description></item><item><title>Adding CRS3 and Pixi to CircleCI pipeline</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/user-sessions/adding-crs3-pixi-to-circleci-pipeline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/user-sessions/adding-crs3-pixi-to-circleci-pipeline/</guid><description>Topic A Web Application Firewall may cause fear it does not fit into DevOps methodology, because a WAF can also block an application‘s legitimate traffic. In this user-session we will see a Continuous Integration pipeline with automated applications tests. The tests are performed against the application Pixi (OWASP DevSlop) with the WAF ModSecurity with the OWASP ModSecurity Core Rule Set 3 in front of the application.
A WAF is an additinal layer of defense against common web application attacks like those described by OWASP Top Ten!</description></item><item><title>Adding security to VSTS pipeline</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/adding-security-to-vsts-pipeline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/adding-security-to-vsts-pipeline/</guid><description>The OWASP DevSlop VSTS pipeline, affectionately known as &amp;ldquo;Patty&amp;rdquo;, needs to produce the absolute most secure code possible, as it is used to release DevSlop.co (our website), it is a proof of concept pipeline. Come help us improve the security of this proof of concept but hacking it and helping us add more checks!
WHY Adding more security to this pipeline means that companies everywhere that use VSTS can adopt this proof of concept internally, adjust it for their specific needs, and starting making more secure apps, very quickly.</description></item><item><title>Agile Practices for Security Teams</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/agile-practices-for-security-teams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/agile-practices-for-security-teams/</guid><description>Until recently, cyber security was often considered as “nice to have” in the software development lifecycle. However, due to several data breaches that hit the headlines, more and more dev teams are now starting to incorporate security practices in their processes. Considering how agile methodologies benefit the development lifecycle, security should be approached in the same, or a similar, way.
Why Agile practices have been around for quite some time now and a lot of organisations incorporate Agile practices into their daily operations.</description></item><item><title>Cloud brokerage - authentication and authorisation</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/dynamic-session/cloud-brokerage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/dynamic-session/cloud-brokerage/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Create a Slack bot in Python</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/user-sessions/create-a-slack-bot-in-python/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/user-sessions/create-a-slack-bot-in-python/</guid><description>Hands on session to show participants how to create a Slack bot in Python</description></item><item><title>Create a Tech Radar for Security teams</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/user-sessions/create-a-tech-radar-for-security-teams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/user-sessions/create-a-tech-radar-for-security-teams/</guid><description>Based on the ideas and tech provided by ThoughtWorks at https://www.thoughtworks.com/radar</description></item><item><title>Creating Appsec metrics and visualisation</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/user-sessions/creating-appsec-metrics-and-visualisation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/user-sessions/creating-appsec-metrics-and-visualisation/</guid><description>Why You can&amp;rsquo;t improve what you don&amp;rsquo;t measure. Its important to measure the activities as part of SDL and drive future improvements to the application security program. Metrics show business value to stakeholders and help drive further investments in the program. Metrics also help in figuring out whats working and whats not.
Metrics used should be meaningful and not there for the sake of just metrics (metric fatigue?).
What The goal of this User Session is to find ways to create meaningful metrics and dashboards for AppSec Professionals like Mean Time To Remediate, Mean Time To Find etc.</description></item><item><title>Defining a Security Champion</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/security-champions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/security-champions/</guid><description>Security Champions are a key element of any AppSec team, since they create a cross-functional team focused on Application Security.
What is a Security Champion?
Security Champions are active members of a team that may help to make decisions about when to engage the Security Team Security Champions act as the &amp;ldquo;voice&amp;rdquo; of security for the given product or team Security Champions assist in the triage of security bugs for their team or area (see definition here)</description></item><item><title>DevSecOps Maturity Model (DSOMM)</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/devsecops-maturity-model/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/devsecops-maturity-model/</guid><description>Start with this http://gdosmm-translation.timo-pagel.de/</description></item><item><title>From Threat Modeling to DevSecOps metrics</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/threat-modeling-to-devsecops/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/threat-modeling-to-devsecops/</guid><description>Why What Content Outcomes Who The target audience for this Working Session is:
Developers Security professionals DevSecOps Security champions References</description></item><item><title>Integrating Security into an Spotify Model (and using Squads for Security teams)</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/integrating-security-into-an-spotify-model/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/integrating-security-into-an-spotify-model/</guid><description>Why The Spotify model of Squads, Chapters, Tribes, and Guilds (using multiple Agile methodologies) has been adopted by many companies. It presents an opportunity to define global practices and activities that can be replicated across multiple teams, geographical locations, and cultures.
We need companies that have tried, failed, and succeeded to integrate security into a Spotify Model to share their experiences.
This working session will focus on increasing our knowledge of how best to integrate Agile Security into the Spotify model.</description></item><item><title>Integrating Security Tools in the SDL</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/integrating-security-tools-in-the-sdl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/integrating-security-tools-in-the-sdl/</guid><description>Most of today´s application security problems can be traced to flaws in the code. It does not matter whether security issues affect operating system components, client applications, web applications, or other systems, most well-known vulnerabilities are caused by coding errors and implementation issues.
The question here is why so many bugs and coding errors continue to cause major security issues when we have had years to deal with these and other common vulnerabilities that are still found in applications today.</description></item><item><title>Integrating Security Tools in the SDL using OWASP DevSecOps Studio</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/user-sessions/integrating-security-tools-in-the-sdl-using-owasp-devsecops-studio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/user-sessions/integrating-security-tools-in-the-sdl-using-owasp-devsecops-studio/</guid><description>Most of today´s application security problems can be traced to flaws in the code. It does not matter whether security issues affect operating system components, client applications, web applications, or other systems, most well-known vulnerabilities are caused by coding errors and implementation issues.
The question here is why so many bugs and coding errors continue to cause major security issues when we have had years to deal with these and other common vulnerabilities that are still found in applications today.</description></item><item><title>Owasp Cloud Security Workshop (BETA)</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/owasp-cloud-security-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/owasp-cloud-security-workshop/</guid><description>The OWASP Cloud Security project aims to help people secure their products and services running in the cloud by providing a set of easy to use threat and control BDD stories that pool together the expertise and experience of the development, operations, and security communities.
This working session is a beta of the project workshop that introduces the following topics:
Behaviour Driven Development (BDD) Threat modeling Using BDD for cloud security WHY We believe that cyber security has a fundamental role to play in protecting the digital future.</description></item><item><title>OWASP Defect Dojo</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/owasp-defect-dojo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/owasp-defect-dojo/</guid><description>An open source vulnerability management tool that streamlines the testing process by offering templating, report generation, metrics, and baseline self-service tools.
DefectDojo is a tracking tool written in Python / Django. DefectDojo was created in 2013 and open-sourced on March 13th, 2015. The project was started to make optimizing vulnerability tracking less painful. The top goal of DefectDojo is to reduce the amount of time security professionals spend logging vulnerabilities. DefectDojo accomplishes this by offering a templating system for vulnerabilities, imports for common vulnerability scanners, report generation, and metrics.</description></item><item><title>OWASP DevSecOps Studio</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/owasp-devsecops-studio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/owasp-devsecops-studio/</guid><description>DevSecOps Studio is one of its kind, self contained DevSecOps environment/distribution to help individuals in learning DevSecOps concepts. It takes lots of efforts to setup the environment for training/demos and more often, its error prone when done manually. DevSecOps Studio is easy to get started, mostly automatic and battle tested during our Free Practical DevSecOps Course at https://www.teachera.io/devsecops-course/
Why and What DevSecOps Studio project aims to reduce the time to bootstrap the environment and help you in concentrating on learning/teaching DevSecOps practices with the following features.</description></item><item><title>Publishing apps in a VSTS security pipeline</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/user-sessions/publishing-apps-in-vsts-security-pipeline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/user-sessions/publishing-apps-in-vsts-security-pipeline/</guid><description>For many people &amp;lsquo;the cloud&amp;rsquo; and DevSecOps can be a bit mysterious. Let&amp;rsquo;s clear this up with a nice, long, slow demo of how to load up an app in your editor, make a change, run it through your pipeline (and pass the security checkes!), then publish it into the cloud. One step at a time.
WHY Absolute beginners in DevOps can learn how to do DevSecOps and publish to the cloud.</description></item><item><title>secureCodeBox - How to improve your CI/CD pipeline with automated security tests</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/user-sessions/using_scb_to_secure_your_pipeline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/user-sessions/using_scb_to_secure_your_pipeline/</guid><description>Awareness of security challenges is crucial for delivering high-quality software. This awareness has to be fostered and applied continuously.
WHY The secureCodeBox provides an open source toolchain for continuous security scanning of your applications. It helps you to find the low-hanging fruit issues early in the development process, freeing the resources of human penetration testers to concentrate on the major security issues. Under the hood we use well-known and open source licensed security scanners like OWASP ZAP, Arachni, NMAP, Nikto, SSLyze.</description></item><item><title>Securing GitHub Integrations</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/securing-github-integrations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/securing-github-integrations/</guid><description>Why This Working Session will examine the need for secure GitHub integrations.
As more and more services are integrated with GitHub, the public and private repos of different companies are being exposed to a much wider set of attackers and threats.
Currently, the GitHub security model does not allow the granularity required to control access (for example read-access to only one repo). This means that choices tend to be limited to either:</description></item><item><title>Securing the CI Pipeline</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/securing-the-ci-pipeline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/securing-the-ci-pipeline/</guid><description>Why This Working Session will consider the securing of the CI Pipeline - A key element of DevOps.
Doing CI builds, testing, and deployments have many advantages when done correctly. Using libraries from 3rd parties in your build can be on compromised servers. Even signing your packages or artifacts automatically could result in you delivering compromised software to others.
What Identify best practice for DevOps and Developers Agree what to include in a cheat sheet for developers who use third party services Agree recommendations for 3rd party service providers (for example, provide warning messages of possible insecurities) Outcomes This Working Session will publish:</description></item><item><title>Security Crowdsourcing</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/security-crowd-sourcing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/security-crowd-sourcing/</guid><description>Security crowdsourcing is necessary - it is allowing highly talented individuals and resourceful organisations to use the power of their intelligence, skills and resources to fight cyber threats. A community can significantly have a higher efficiency level in fighting against cyber threats rather than a single body that does all by itself.
Sharing Intelligence
Effective form of crowdsourcing, governments and private companies can share their knowledge and stop or reduce potential or existing threats.</description></item><item><title>Share your playbooks and release them under Creative Commons</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/user-sessions/share-your-playbooks-and-release-them-under-cc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/user-sessions/share-your-playbooks-and-release-them-under-cc/</guid><description>Session to consolidate and publish anonymised real-word playbooks (provided by Summit partipants)</description></item><item><title>SOC Monitoring Visualisation</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/appsec-soc-monitoring-visualisation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/appsec-soc-monitoring-visualisation/</guid><description>Why Capturing logs and visualising them in a SOC (Security Operation Center) is a key activity in the asymmetric arms race against malicious actors and bugs.
In addition to providing high-value actionable information, a good SOC will provide a wealth of valuable metrics and visualisations for the business, from user activities and behaviour to system performance.
The Working Session will assess the role, the work, and the importance of a SOC within a business.</description></item><item><title>Using activity-oriented metrics for Security</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/activity-oriented-metrics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/activity-oriented-metrics/</guid><description>WHY Gamification of security activities is a great way to engage with teams.
Scorecard to provide better information, fun and gamification.
It uses RAG report data and provides an extra level of insights on each team. We can see the data by feature (service) team, department and for a full matrix of everything.
Every teams and services can be listed and who owns what, from the Tiering of the service to specific services (web sites, apis, databases, workers, lambdas…).</description></item><item><title>Using JIRA to create and execute Security Playbooks</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/user-sessions/using-jira-to-create-and-execute-security-playbooks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/user-sessions/using-jira-to-create-and-execute-security-playbooks/</guid><description>Hands on session on how to use JIRA for incident response</description></item><item><title>Web Application Honeypot</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/web-application-honeypot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/web-application-honeypot/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re rebooting the OWASP Distributed Web Application Honeypot Project which Ryan Barnett used to lead and fell dormant due to a change of employer. We now have the capacity to host a new community reporting server in ARU&amp;rsquo;s new research lab (as well as plenty of physical server capacity).
WHY Planning to work with the OWASP ModSec Core Rule Set Project leaders to develop a new honeypot VM OVA/OVF (and potentially a docker image as well) based around the latest version of CRS as a way of generating threat intelligence data available to the community.</description></item><item><title>WebAuthn - Getting started workshop</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/webauthn-getting-started-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/webauthn-getting-started-workshop/</guid><description>See how this Web Authentication: What It Is and What It Means for Passwords
WHY WebAuthn is a JS API for public key credential management. It&amp;rsquo;s a part of FIDO2 project, who&amp;rsquo;s goal is to develop modern secure, pfishing-proof, easy to use protocol. WebAuthn will be available in all major browsers, and so this will drastically change security state of the web, finally bringing passwordless, phishing-prof authentication to every site.</description></item><item><title>Writing security tests to confirm vulnerabilities and fixes</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/user-sessions/writing-security-tests-to-confirm-vulnerabilities-and-fixes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/user-sessions/writing-security-tests-to-confirm-vulnerabilities-and-fixes/</guid><description>Hands on session writing security tests
See previous summit session on this topic</description></item></channel></rss>