<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Agile on Open Security Summit 2018</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/topics/agile/</link><description>Recent content in Agile on Open Security Summit 2018</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://2018.open-security-summit.org/topics/agile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Agile Practices for Security Teams</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/agile-practices-for-security-teams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/agile-practices-for-security-teams/</guid><description>Until recently, cyber security was often considered as “nice to have” in the software development lifecycle. However, due to several data breaches that hit the headlines, more and more dev teams are now starting to incorporate security practices in their processes. Considering how agile methodologies benefit the development lifecycle, security should be approached in the same, or a similar, way.
Why Agile practices have been around for quite some time now and a lot of organisations incorporate Agile practices into their daily operations.</description></item><item><title>Integrating Security into an Spotify Model (and using Squads for Security teams)</title><link>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/integrating-security-into-an-spotify-model/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://2018.open-security-summit.org/tracks/devsecops/working-sessions/integrating-security-into-an-spotify-model/</guid><description>Why The Spotify model of Squads, Chapters, Tribes, and Guilds (using multiple Agile methodologies) has been adopted by many companies. It presents an opportunity to define global practices and activities that can be replicated across multiple teams, geographical locations, and cultures.
We need companies that have tried, failed, and succeeded to integrate security into a Spotify Model to share their experiences.
This working session will focus on increasing our knowledge of how best to integrate Agile Security into the Spotify model.</description></item></channel></rss>